憶往昔
艾德和哈里  抓鬼特工隊
Ed and harry -- the Ghostfacers.
你們在這搞什么
What the hell are you doing here?
我們屬于這里
Uh, we belong here.
我們是專業人員
We're professionals.
專業的什么
Professional what?
超自然事件調查
Paranormal investigators.
就是這東西  它能使我們獲得一切
This stuff right here -- this is our ticket to the big time --
名望  金錢  和姑娘...
fame, money, sex...
滾床單
with girls.
我們是家人
We are family.
我們之間的一切問題
Everything that has ever gone wrong between us
其實都因為我們是家人
has been because we're family.
那怎么  我們從此不再是家人了嗎
So, what? We're not family now?
我是說既然你想好好合作  那就合作
I'm saying you want to work, let's work.
你說我們以后都公事公辦
You said that you wanted to keep things strictly business.
我說的公事公辦是指你我之間的關系
I wanted to keep things strictly business between us.
你那天說的話
About what you said the other day...
我以為你不在乎呢
I thought it didn't bother you.
我可能是沒考慮周全
I may not think things all the way through,
但我那么做  是因為那是該做的事
but what I do, I do because it's the right thing.
你并不是為了我而救我
You didn't save me for me.
你是為了自己
You did it for you.
如今
華盛頓州  斯普林代爾
媽媽
Mom?
媽媽  你在家嗎
Mom, are you home?
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
翻譯 草草   愛卿遛小鳥   泓   Reginamoon
時間軸 憑陵新月   兜兜兜爹   愛卿遛小鳥
校對 草草   米蘇   總監 米蘇   后期 灰灰是菇涼
911  請問你有什么緊急情況
911. What is your emergency?
我屋里有個人
There's someone in my room.
你在哪
What is your location?
你能說出你的地址嗎  女士
Can you give us a location, ma'am?
你還在聽嗎
Are you still there?
女士  請不要掛電話
Ma'am, please do not hang up.
我開始追蹤你的電話了
I've begun tracing your call,
你得保持通話
but I need you to stay on the line for me.
請保持通話
Stay on the line.
我們會派警官
We'll send out an officer...
兇鬼惡靈
第九季 第十五集
#瘦人
我就回來
All right. I'll be back.
等等
Wait.
你去哪
Where you headed?
華盛頓州  我找到一樁案子
Washington. I caught a case.
不要我一起去嗎
You want me to come with?
你想來嗎
Do you want to come?
去獵魔嗎
On a hunt?
為什么不去呢
Why wouldn't I?
不知道
I don't know, man.
因為你最近讓我找不到北
'cause lately with you, up is down and down is sideways, you know?
我不知道你想干什么
I-I ... I don't know what you want.
好吧  你想來嗎
Okay. You want in?
好啊
Fine.
沒問題
Sure thing.
犯罪現場流出的照片
Photo leaked from the crime scene.
那女孩在自己房間被殺
Girl was murdered in her room,
門窗都鎖著
doors were locked, the windows were locked.
壁畫先生是誰
Who's the wallflower?
問得是啊
Exactly.
我猜  被拍下來的鬼魂
Best guest ... ghost caught on film.
你要來啊
So, you're coming.
你覺得我像是要留下嗎
Does it look like I'm staying?
華盛頓州  斯普林代爾
我洗了好幾個小時
I scrubbed for hours.
還得把地毯扯下來
I'll have to rip up the carpet.
我女兒  凱茜
My daughter, Casey...
地毯的顏色還是她自己選的
she picked out the color herself.
請節哀  邁爾斯太太
We're...very sorry for your loss, Mrs. Miles.
你說凱茜沒有什么敵人
You mentioned Casey had no known enemies.
那在家呢
What about at home?
你注意到發生過什么不尋常的事嗎
Anything unusual you may have noticed?
電路異常  燈閃爍什么的
Uh...electricity acting up or lights...flickering,
電視出毛病
TV on the fritz?
沒有什么問題
No, no fritzing.
也沒有什么寒氣
No cold spots, either.
抱歉  我想問一句
Sorry. Out of curiosity, uh...
你為什么要說到寒氣
Why do you mention cold spots?
抱歉  聽起來一定很怪  但是
I'm sorry. That must sound strange, but...
已經三天了
...it's been three days since...
而警方一無所獲
And the police have found nothing.
我不得不賣掉房子
I'd h... I'd have to sell my house
雇傭私家偵探
to afford a private investigator,
所以那些超自然論者打來電話時
so when the supernaturalists called ...
等等  什么
Whoa, uh, sorry, the...
超自然論者
Um... supernaturalists?
我知道聯調局會覺得這不合常理
I know to the FBI it's not exactly orthodox.
但這些人知道別人不知道的事
But these men had answers that no one else had, and I ...
我欠凱茜的
I owe it to Casey...
我至少要聽聽
to listen.
他們提起寒氣的事是因為
Now, they ... they brought up cold spots in relation to...?
大概是超自然現象吧
Signs of the paranormal, I suppose.
他們今天會過來看一眼
They're coming by today to take a look.
這些超自然論者告訴你他們叫什么了嗎
And did these supernaturalists give you a name?
抓鬼特工隊
Ghostfacers.
真見鬼
Son of a bitch.
看啊  我們又多了兩個粉絲
Oh, wow, look. We got two more followers.
是啊  哈里
Yeah. Harry,
應該是我們那次圖書館的采訪
I think it's from that library interview we did.
很好
Nice.
伙計
Hey, pal.
唐娜又發了什么
What did Dana post?
她改了她的頭像
No, it's just ... she changed her profile pic,
雖然裁過了
and it's cropped,
但能清楚地看到有個男人摟著她
but you can clearly see a guy's arm around her.
而她還笑得那么開心
And she's smiling like the dickens.
是啊
Yeah.
或許他們只是純潔的友誼
Uh, it ... it could a platonic...
那個摟著她的人
arm that's touching her.
溫家兄弟  太好了
Ah, the Winchesters. Yay.
-從沒有人  -這么覺得
- Says nobody. - Ever.
給我閉嘴聽好  我們這么做
All right, shut up and listen. This is how it's gonna go.
你們兩個小丑  給我鉆進外面那輛破車里
You two clowns are gonna get into that mystery machine outside,
然后給我滾蛋
and you're gonna leave town
否則我就打穿你們的膝蓋
or I'm gonna put holes in your knees.
你們需要點什么嗎
Can I get you guys anything? Something, uh...
可以埋單了
Uh, we're ready for the Bill.
這張盤子上還有臟東西
There's still crud on this plate.
立刻去給我洗干凈
Now, hit the sinks and do it right.
抱歉  特里
Sorry, Trey.
首先
Ahh, first of all,
我們不怕你們
you guys don't scare us.
一點也不怕
Not at all.
跟我的槍打個招呼吧
Say, "hola" to my little pistola.
你是在向我炫耀肚臍毛
Am I supposed to be impressed with that treasure trail
還是塞在褲子里的女槍
or the lady gun you got hiding in your, uh, pants there?
兩者都有
Uh...both?
不管你們怎么想
Look, whether you like it or not,
我們要處理這件事
we are handling this situation.
-沒錯  -是嗎
- Yup. - Really?
因為我看到的是一對兒為名利忘乎所以的家伙
'cause I see a couple of fame whores
拿著攝像機拍攝一個剛失去女兒的母親
who are pointing their camera at a mom who just lost her kid.
伙計們  我們是調查員
Guys, we are investigators,
我們完全有權利
and we have every right ...
不  你們沒有  知道為什么嗎
No. No, you don't. You know why?
因為你們只會礙事
'cause you're just gonna get in our way.
或者害死別的什么人
Or you're gonna get somebody else killed.
沒錯  你們要么識相點自己離開
That's right. So, you can either walk out of here...
要么就爬出去  自己選
...or crawl. Up to you.
天吶  你們能不能放松點
Oh, my God, menudo. Will you guys relax?
我們心里有數
We know what we're going.
-沒錯  -是嗎
- Yup. - Really?
那你們其他的隊員呢
And what about the rest of the bad news bears, huh?
那個胖子哪去了
Where's the ... where's the fat one?
還有個女孩  有個女孩吧
And ... and the girl? There was a girl, right?
他們  我們不要他們了  他們是累贅
They ... we dropped them. They were ... they were dead weight.
他們還活著
Well, t-they're still alive.
他們絕對還活著
They're ... no, they're totally alive.
懂了  現在就剩你們倆傻瓜了
I see. So, it's just the, uh, the dumpy duo, then.
真是太棒了
Well, that's great.
事實是這樣的
So, here's the deal. A ghost...
你們倆不到五分鐘就會死在鬼的手里
will land you two dead in five seconds flat.
鬼
A ghost?
他們以為是鬼
They think it's a ghost.
-絕對不是鬼  -不
- It's so not a ghost. - No.
好吧  你們說
Okay. We'll bite.
你們覺得是什么
What do you think it is?
這次我來好嗎
Can I ... can I do it this time?
-行啊  -好的
- You got it. - Okay.
我等這一刻等一輩子了
I've waited all my life for this.
吃癟吧  賤人們
Amazon me, bitches.
我會開槍斃了你的
I will shoot you...
賤人們
bitches.
我們剛剛說到  你們這就要走了  是吧
Like we were saying, you were just going, right?
很好
Great.
談話愉快
Good talk.
我看他們是蛋白質吃多了
50 shades of way too much protein.
捉鬼特工隊  《瘦人揭秘》
迪恩
Uh...Dean?
嗯
Yeah?
艾德和哈里寫了本書
Ed and Harry wrote a book.
-什么  -嗯
- What? - Yeah.
《瘦人揭秘》
Uh, "The skinny on Thinman"
作者是美國最頂尖的超自然論者
by America's foremost supernaturalists.
什么是
What the hell's a Thinman?
不知道
I don't know. Um...
看啊
Whoa. Check that out, though.
這看上去的確像是凱茜·邁爾斯身后的那個東西
That does kind of look like whatever was behind Casey Miles, right?
或者被削掉臉皮的蓋思
Or Garth if somebody shaved his face off.
有什么了不起
Big whoop.
這兒呢  瘦人
Here we go. Uh, "Thinman ...
最早流傳于網絡的都市傳說
an urban legend started on the world wide web ...
會在目標生活的背景中徘徊
lurks in the background of his victims' lives
直到他決定下手
until he's ready to kill them."
網上的一切都是真的嘛
Yeah, because everything started on the internet is true.
比如鯊魚襲擊直升機
Like, uh, oh, the shark attacking a helicopter ...
他們也寫書講那個了嗎
They write the book on that one, too?
伙計  不管是不是真的
Dude, real or not,
這網站上有幾千人發帖了呢
thousands of people have posted to the site.
瘦人好像是新的大腳怪
It's like Thinman is the new bigfoot or something.
或許瘦人只是名字新奇的鬼魂
Or Thinman is just a ghost with a brand name.
你這么說是因為你真認為
You saying that 'cause you really think
是鬼魂還是單純因為你討厭捉鬼特工隊
it's a ghost or because you don't like the ghostfacers?
別忘了  我們在凱茜屋里探測到了電磁信號
Hey, don't forget ... we hit EMF in Casey's room.
但是那房子旁邊有電線
Right, but the house was next door to power lines,
會影響讀書
which can affect the read.
一個女孩死在密室里  薩姆
A girl died in a locked room, Sam ...
顯然就是鬧鬼
spells "ghost" right there.
或許它在房屋上鎖之前進去了
Maybe it got in there before it was locked up.
誰知道呢  迪恩
Who knows, Dean?
但是怎么可能世界各地的人們都看到了一樣的鬼
But how can people all over the world see the same ghost?
鬼魂可不會到處跑
Spirits don't exactly hop around.
我知道
I know that.
但現在隔界里各種亂套
But right now, the veil is all kinds of screwed, okay?
鬼魂說不定能滿地出現呢
Ghosts could be popping up anywhere.
但是  迪恩  瘦人目擊事件幾年前就開始了
Yeah, but, Dean, Thinman sightings date back a couple years.
隔界的問題只有六個月吧
The veil's only been a problem for, what, the last six months?
現在還到處有人說看見貓王了呢
Well, you know, people still see Elvis all over the damn place.
我只是說那倆二貨
Look, all I'm saying is those douchewheels
不是任何方面的專家
ain't experts on crap.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
查當地死亡名單
I'm checking the local deaths
看有沒有誰可能是那個鬼
to see if there's any candidates for ghosts.
壁櫥  凱茜度過生命黃昏的地方
The closet ... the setting of the sunset of Casey's life.
哈里
Harry.
嗯
Yeah.
行了  伙計  別再用臉書
Come on, man, would you please stop
跟蹤你的前女友了
facebook stalking your ex-girlfriend?
我沒說錯
I was right.
她把感情狀態改為"一言難盡"
She changed her relationship status to "It's complicated."
這算什么啊
What does that even mean?
誰管呢  是你甩了她
Who cares? You broke up with her.
那女孩的一切都一言難盡
Everything about that girl is complicated.
她拿到奶油松餅
Okay, I mean, she gets the cream puffs,
還非要扔掉里面的餡
she tells you to take out the filling.
那是松餅啊
They're just puffs.
是啊  她的確挺有病的
Yeah, that was some pretty messed-up stuff.
好吧  抱歉
Uh, okay. I'm ... I'm sorry.
好了
Mm. Okay.
沒事了
I'm good.
-好了嗎  -恢復狀態了
- Okay? - Back on game. Yeah.
我們就要找到瘦人了  艾德
We're so close to finding Thinman, Ed.
我能聞到他了
I can smell him.
我能聞到他的獠牙
I can smell his musk.
從未如此接近
Closer than ever.
-這事真的很嚴肅  哈里  -是啊
- This is really serious, Harry. - Yeah.
溫家兄弟也來了  你也知道
I mean, the Winchesters are here, and, you know,
我可不想被薩姆和迪恩打穿膝蓋
I don't want my knees blown off by Sam and Dean.
你有沒有考慮過或許我們該  別管這事了
Have you ever thought that we might just, you know, bail on this?
什么
What?
你是怎么了
What the ... what the hell is wrong with you?!
我們不能讓那倆肌肉男搶走我們的榮譽
We can't let those jockstraps steal our glory.
誰管他們怎么想  他們連推特都沒有
No one cares what they think. They don't even have a twitter.
我們會找到瘦人的  艾德
We're gonna find Thinman, Ed,
為了我們的家人  和唐娜
for our families, for Dana.
你是為了讓你前女友后悔嗎
Oh, so, it's about your ex eating her words?
是為了讓所有黑后悔
It's about making all the haters eat their words.
瑪姬  斯布魯斯  那些逃兵
Maggie and Spruce ... the just ... deserters.
想過什么"正常生活"
They want to lead a "normal life""
什么意思啊
I mean, what is that?
去他們的
Screw them.
-去他們的  -太對了
- Screw them. - Right?
等我們找到瘦人  是他們會上《菲爾醫生》嗎
When we find Thinman, are they gonna be on "Dr. Phil""
脫口秀
不是
No.
是我們會上《菲爾醫生》
We're gonna be on "Dr. Phil."
沒錯  開始錄影吧
Hell, yeah. Press "record," buddy.
好嘞
You got it.
等等
Wait for it.
-好了嗎  -嗯
- You ready? - Yep.
一個年輕女孩的閨房有兩個用處
The bedroom of a teenage girl is meant for two things ...
歡笑和快樂
giggles and joy.
直到一晚
Until one night,
瘦人將歡笑變成流血
Thinman turned the giggles into blood.
你現在氣場太棒了
Oh! You are so money right now.
-你喜歡嗎  -真的很不錯
- You like that? - This is good stuff.
會有很多女人喜歡上這個的  艾德
And it's gonna pay off in ladies, Ed ... lots of ladies.
我們會需要通氣管
We're gonna need ... we're gonna need snorkels,
因為我們將暢游在...
'cause we're gonna be swimming around in so much ...
我覺得你們可能會渴了
Thought you boys might be thirsty.
謝謝  聽上去很好喝
Please. That sounds delicious.
好了  過去六個月里
Okay. All right, over the past six months,
斯普林代爾有三起非自然死亡
there have been three unnatural deaths in Springdale,
但都與凱茜·邁爾斯無關
none of them connected to Casey Miles,
而且都不是很慘
and none of them violent.
這樣的事應該不會產生復仇鬼魂
Okay, that's not exactly a recipe for a vengeful spirit.
但有很多未解的死亡懸案
There have been a bunch of unexplained deaths
被歸為瘦人所為
pinned on Thinman.
一個人死了  幾周后
Um, a vic dies, then, a couple weeks later,
會發現死者的某張照片里有瘦人
a photo pops up of the vic with Thinman photobombing.
瘦人
那么瘦人是跟蹤狂嗎
So, Thinman's stalking folks?
根據傳聞是這樣
According to the lore.
是傻子這么說吧
According to the idiots.
我們怎么沒注意到這些被害人
How come none of these vics pinged our radar?
應該是這些神秘死亡
I'm pretty sure the mysterious deaths
可以用非超自然原因解釋
can be chalked up to non-supernatural causes.
還有就是
That and, honestly,
瘦人
這些照片大部分看上去挺假的
Most of these photos look pretty fake.
包括凱茜的嗎
Even Casey's?
除了凱茜的
Except Casey's.
凱茜的照片沒有修改過
Casey's photo... wasn't doctored.
她身后的那東西真的是在那兒
Whatever was behind her... was really there.
這完全說不通啊
Okay, well, that doesn't make any sense.
這世上怎么能有東西又真又假
I mean, how could something be both real and fake at the same time?
有個女孩死了  這個絕對假不了
Well, a girl is dead, and that's about as real as it gets.
她做的最后一件事
All right, so, the last thing she did
是用手機照了相
was she took a photo on her phone.
這張照片怎么流傳到網上的
How did that photo end up online?
不知道
No clue.
最早是發在一個瘦人粉絲網站上的
It was originally posted to a Thinman fan forum,
但IP地址卻查不到
but the I.P. address was blocked.
這東西還有粉絲
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait. This thing has fans?
當然了
Of course it does.
那么肯定有人希望照片流傳到網上
Okay, well, then somebody wanted this photo on the internet,
而且肯定不是鬼魂上網發布的
and I'm guessing that the ghost didn't hop online to post it.
警長在嗎
Is the, uh, sheriff around?
我們想問他幾個問題
There's a couple questions we'd like to ask him.
抱歉了
Uh, sorry to disappoint.
警長去打獵了
Sheriff's on a hunting trip.
但是很感謝你們能來
But, uh, I appreciate you agents being here.
我真是很需要幫忙
I could use all the help I can get.
等等  你發現這個時它就被摔壞了嗎
Wait a second. Was this cracked when you found it?
嗯  或許她失手掉了
Yeah, man. Maybe she dropped it?
911電話在11點59時斷了
911 call went dead at 11:59.
照片發布的時間呢
Wait, what time was the photo posted?
大概凌晨2點
Around 2:00 a.m.
但是驗尸官認定死亡時間是午夜
But the coroner has the death at midnight.
那她是怎么用手機發布照片的
How could she have posted the photo from her phone?
這根本不可能
That ... that's impossible.
或者是超自然現象
Or...supernatural.
什么
What?
你為什么這么說
Why would you say that?
有幾個人來過  問了些關于這案子的問題
A couple fellas came by, uh, asking questions about the girl's death,
說他們可能能幫上忙
suggested they might be able to help.
他們給了我一本他們寫的書  關于...
They, uh, gave me a book they wrote about, um...
瘦人嗎
Thinman?
對
Yeah.
不喜歡嗎
Not a fan?
蘋果餐館
探員  謝謝你們能來
Agents, thanks for coming.
那兩個二貨在這兒干什么
What are these two crapshoots doing here?
我覺得整點《靈媒緝兇》那套也沒什么壞處
I figured it wouldn't hurt to go a little "Medium," you know?
跟我們隔兩個郡  大家在到處找一個
Uh...two counties over, folks were combing the place
8月份失蹤的可憐的小男孩
for a poor little dead boy back in August.
警方找了一個靈媒去
The cops let a psychic do her thing.
第二天就找到了尸體
Shish, bang, boom ... found a body a day later.
失陪
Excuse me.
有監控錄像嗎
Is there any, uh, security-cam footage.
有
Uh, yeah, just...
不是叫你們滾蛋嗎
I thought I told you to beat it.
你們要把我趕出去嗎  "探員"
Oh, well, what are you gonna do. You gonna out me, "agent"?
在犯罪現場玩狗仔隊
Okay, look, playing paparazzi at a crime scene ...
除了對你們  對其他人有任何益處嗎
Who does that help but yourselves?
還有博主  迪恩  那些信徒
The bloggers, Dean, the believers ...
那些需要一些證明
Everyone who needs just a little proof
確信瘦人的確存在的人
to know that Thinman is out there.
你們是說網上有很多人
Wait, so, you're saying there's a lot of folks online
對這個瘦人很死忠
that are pretty die-hard about this thing?
-那可不是  -當然了
- Oh, yeah. - Oh, yeah. Uh-huh.
如果加上適當的西藏字符
You throw the right Tibetan symbol into the mix,
你們倆蠢貨想沒想過瘦人變成幻像怪成真了
you dumb asses ever think the Thinman comes to life as a tulpa?
因為幾千人對瘦人的描述是統一的嗎
Because thousands of people can agree that Thinman is any one thing?
關于瘦人的傳言千變萬化
The lore changes blog to blog.
不是幻像怪
He's not a tulpa.
好吧
Okay, all right. All right.
不說廢話了
Right here, right now, cut the crap.
那你們倆真的知道瘦人是什么嗎
Do either of you actually know what Thinman is?
不  我們只是在電視上扮演超自然論者
No. We just play supernaturalists on tv.
我們完全不知道我們在干什么
We have no idea what we're doing.
我們當然知道了
Of course we do.
瘦人是半人半樹
Thinman is part man, part tree.
有人認為他來自一個
Some people believe that he emerged
自閉癥男孩的惡魔
from the nightmare of an autistic boy.
就是說你們也不知道
All right, so you have no idea.
伙計們  過來看看
Fellas, you want to see this.
快看
All right, check it out.
他怎么從停車場突然進入餐館的
All right, so, how did he jump from the parking lot to the diner.
門是鎖著的嗎
The doors were locked?
錄像顯示特雷10分鐘前才鎖上的
The footage shows Trey locked them 10 minutes before.
鎖沒鎖都不重要
Locked, not locked, it doesn't matter.
大家都知道瘦人能瞬間移動
Everyone knows Thinman can teleport.
我的電磁探測器毫無反應
I didn't even get a blip on my EMF.
或許不是鬼
So, maybe it's not a ghost.
二位探員也信這些了
You Feds believers now?
那我們走了
Okay, uh... we're gonna go.
-副警長  探員  干得好  -我們走吧
- Good work, deputy, agents. - Let's go. Let's go, man.
再看一遍
See it again.
天吶
Holy wow.
有人把瘦人的餐館視頻
Someone posted the diner footage of Thinman
發在我們博客的評論區了
in the comments section of our blog.
-誰啊  -管他呢
- Who? - Who cares?
保持速度
Maintain current velocity.
你為什么把忍者衣服穿上了
Hey, wh-why are you putting your ninja outfit on?
我可不能等到再出人命
I'm not gonna wait for someone else to die.
我今晚就要找到瘦人
I'm gonna find Thinman tonight.
-在哪  -當然是林子里
- Where? - The woods, obvi.
這太籠統了吧
Uh, that's kind of general.
據傳說  瘦人在樹旁邊出沒
Well, the lore says that Thinman hangs out by trees,
而林子里都是樹
and the woods is where trees hang out.
兩起命案  他肯定在本地的林子里
Two kills in town ... local woods is the best bet.
有兩個人死了  真的死了
Two people are dead ... really dead.
我總是忘不了這個
And I just keep thinking that, you know,
也許該讓薩姆和迪恩接手
maybe Sam and Dean should just take over.
首先  絕對不行
First of all, hell no.
再者  別再掃我的興了[在我的彩虹上下雨]
And ... and quit raining on my rainbow.
沒有雨就沒有彩虹
Rainbows can't happen without rain.
別用科學對付我
Don't try to use science with me.
這是一種情感
This is about a-a feeling.
我們不能現在放棄
And we can't quit
我們馬上就能找到瘦人
when we're so close to finding Thinman
終于能彌補我們為了做這件事
and finally making up for everything we've lost
而失去的一切
because of...what we do.
但其實交給專業人士
Okay, it wouldn't be the worst idea, though, you know,
其實也不是什么壞主意
if we leave it to the professionals.
我們就是專業人士  艾德
We are the professionals, Ed.
去樹林嗎
So, the woods?
隨便哪片樹林  艾德  隨便
Any woods, Ed. Any woods.
好吧
Okay.
我只是病急亂投醫  但說到瞬移
Just grasping at straws here, but when I think "teleport,"
我就想到"十字路口惡魔"
I think "crossroads demon."
喜歡捅人看視頻網站的惡魔  好啊
Demon that likes to stab and watch youtube. Why not?
對了  說起那個
Oh, by the way, speaking of which,
特里被刀捅死的視頻
the video of, uh, Trey getting knifed --
已經掛上網了
it's already online.
有兩千人看過
It has, like, 2,000 views.
好像有人故意要讓大家看到瘦人行兇
It's like somebody wants people to see Thinman in action.
因為會有人看  因為那些人很變態
It's 'cause people will watch, 'cause people are sick.
什么時候病毒視頻從小猩猩掉下樹
And when did "viral" go from that baby chimp
變成殺手偷拍了
falling out of a tree to killer "candid camera"?
你知道什么視頻會在網上瘋傳嗎
You know what video would have gone viral,
只可惜那個沒留下來
if we still had it?
你五歲時扮成蝙蝠俠的樣子
When you were five and you got dressed up as Batman
從棚屋上跳了下來
and you jumped off the shed
因為你以為自己會飛
'cause you thought you could fly.
你先跳的
After you jumped first.
我當時九歲  而且我扮的是超人好嗎
Hey, I was nine, and I was dressed up like Superman, okay?
地球人都知道蝙蝠俠不會飛
Everybody knows that Batman can't fly.
我當時不知道  摔斷了胳膊
Well, I didn't know that. I broke my arm.
是啊
I know you did.
我讓你坐在我的車把上送你去了急診室
Man, I drove you to the E.R. on my handlebars.
真是快樂時光啊
Well, good times.
是啊
Yeah, they were.
進來吧
Come on in.
我有很重要的事要告訴你們
I got to tell you guys something important,
然后這案子就歸你們了
and then the case is yours.
我是哈里  一個人的抓鬼特工隊
Harry here, solo Ghostfacer,
正在在樹林里調查潛在
investigating a possible Thinman habitat...
瘦人棲息地
in the woods.
孤身一人  深入樹林
All alone, deep in the woods,
離死亡之刃這么近
a man could lose his marbles
會讓人喪失理智
being so close to the blade of doom.
幸運的是  我清醒得很
Lucky for us, I'm really good at marbles.
要做抓鬼特工隊  就專心一意
All right, either you bleed ghostfacers red or you don't.
斯布魯斯想辦公司
If Spruce wanted to start a startup
瑪姬一心要玩輪滑
and Maggie's heart was in the roller derby,
我憑什么阻止他們
who am I to stop them?
但是哈里  我不能讓他屈服于他的女友
But Harry -- I-I couldn't let him give in to his girl.
她說抓鬼特工隊很蠢
I mean, she -- she called the Ghostfacers stupid.
蠢  你們能相信嗎
Stupid! Can you -- can you believe that?
我可不管
You know, I-I don't care
她爸的對沖基金有多少錢
how much money her daddy's hedge fund has.
我不能看著哈里變成公司的走狗
I just couldn't watch Harry become a corporate stooge.
聽起來像是碧池蒙德高中的悲慘時光
Okay, this all sounds like sad times at bitchmont high.
取自電影Fast Times at Ridgemont High  雷奇蒙德的快樂時光
跟案子有什么關系
What does this have to do with the case?
哈里要離開
Harry was gonna leave,
我得給他一個留下的理由
so I needed to give him a reason to stay.
我編造了瘦人
I-I made up Thinman.
瘦人跟蹤被害人
Thinman stalks his victims,
但局勢反轉了  朋友們
but the tables have turned, my friends.
跟蹤狂變成了被跟蹤的人
The stalker is now the stalkee.
你是說這破事根本就是假的
So you're saying that this crap is actually crap?
一張管家的老照片  后期好好處理一番
One old photo of a butler, a lot of photoshop later,
我匿名發在一個恐怖論壇上
and I posted on one of those horror forums under "anonymous"
就火了起來
and it blew up.
我只我們偽造了一件案子
Yeah. I only faked one case for us,
我們準備收拾東西回家時
and then we're packing up to go home
有人在網上說見到了瘦人
when somebody posted a sighting of Thinman,
于是我們就去追查  后來瘦人
so...we went after it, and that's how the Thinman
就成了大眾傳說
became a crowdsourced legend.
我們是領頭羊
Look, we were at the front of it.
這感覺很奇妙
It felt like something.
有追隨者的感覺很好
It -- it was so awesome to have a following,
哈里  非常沉迷
and Harry -- he was just -- he was so into it.
艾德  你得告訴他
Ed, you have to tell him.
你不明白
You don't get it.
我們是追蹤瘦人的人
We were the Thinman guys.
沒有瘦人  我們就是普通人
Without the Thinman, we're just...guys --
就是  蠢男
just -- we're just puffs.
-什么  -什么
- What? - What?
如果我告訴哈里  他就會離開抓鬼特工隊
If I tell Harry, he's gonna leave the Ghostfacers.
你不告訴他  他還是會離開
Listen, if you don't tell him, he's gonna leave anyway.
相信我
Trust me here.
秘密會毀掉兩個人的關系
Secrets ruin relationships.
好吧  等時機成熟我就告訴他
Okay, well, I'll just tell him when the time is right.
現在時機就很好  伙計
Time's right now, chief.
他現在不在
Well, he's -- he's not here.
他在樹林里
Uh, he's -- he's out in the woods,
尋找瘦人
uh, searching for Thinman.
瘦人  不管這是什么鬼東西
Okay, because Thinman, or whatever the hell this thing is,
已經殺死兩個人了  現在哈里又只身在樹林里
has killed two people, and now Harry is in the woods alone.
其實算不上是樹林啦
Well, actually, it's more like "wood," um,
我讓他在雜貨店后面的幾棵樹邊下車了
'cause I dropped him off by some trees behind a grocery store.
拜托  他不會有事的
Guys, come on. He's gonna be fine.
伙計們
Guys?
好了  這是個  是個
All right, what we have here is a, uh, -- it's a --
好像是個木棍
it looks like a formation
堆起來搭成的陣型
of sticks in the shape of a pile.
可能是瘦人留下的
Could have been left here for us by Thinman.
那是什么
What was that?
天哪
Oh, my God.
這兒還有其他東西
We are not alone.
太緊了嗎
Too tight?
沒有  我很好
Nope. No, I'm good. I'm good.
-我沒事  -好吧
- I'm good. - All right.
等我們回旅館
I think I'm just gonna have to staple it
我再好好處理一下
when we get back to the motel.
我們是對的  艾德  真有瘦人
We were right, Ed! Thinman's real.
那里有新留下的胎痕
Yeah. Some fresh tires tracks back over there.
-我拍了照  -干什么
- I took some photos. - What for?
那輛車可能屬于割傷你的人
Because that car might belong to whoever knifed you.
割傷我的是瘦人
Well, whoever cut me was Thinman,
瘦人不開車
and Thinman doesn't drive.
真是瘦人  混球
It was Thinman, jackass!
不用我一一給你們解釋吧
I mean, I shouldn't have to connect the dots for you guys.
我以為你倆都挺聰明的
I figured, you know, you're both intelligent, m-maybe.
哈里
Um, Harry.
怎么了
What?
你之前怎么不說
Why didn't you tell me that before?
因為  我不知道
Because -- I-I don't know --
我想你會生我的氣
I thought you were gonna get mad.
想得沒錯  艾德
Oh, good guess, Ed.
我是生氣了
I am mad.
我現在非常非常生你的氣
I'm really, really mad at you right now.
我看出來了
I-I can see that.
你毀掉了我們的生活
You crashed the Jenga tower of our lives.
我本來要結婚了
I was gonna get married.
我離開她  跟你東奔西跑  生活在謊言之中
I left her to run around with you, living some lie.
至少咱倆都在
Well, at least we were living it together.
你不是吧
Seriously? Seriously?
如果我沒有編造瘦人的事
If I hadn't struck gold with Thinman,
你這會兒正做著無聊的工作  算著無聊的數字
you'd be doing a boring job, doing boring numbers,
唯唐娜爸爸之命是從
answering to Dana's dad.
我救了你  老兄
Okay? I saved you, bud.
救我  免于什么
Saved me? From what?!
免于過上好日子
From living a nice life?
免于不被刀捅傷
From not getting stabbed?
你還能再自私一點嗎
How selfish can you be?
也許現在還不晚
Well, maybe it's not too late, you know?
你可以打給她試試
You could call her and see.
-沒用的  -也許能行呢
- That's not gonna work. - Well, maybe -- maybe it will.
沒用的  想知道為什么嗎
No, it's not. You want to know why?
因為已經有個男人摟著她了
'cause she's got some guy's arm wrapped around her neck,
她的狀態是"一言難盡"  好嗎
and it's "complicated" okay?
哈里  我們一開始并不知道
Look, Harry, we didn't know from the start
瘦人是真是假
if Thinman was real or not.
也許我是有一些內幕
I -- okay, look, maybe I had some inside knowledge,
但如果我們是為了粉絲堅持下去
okay, but does it really make a difference
那跟以前有什么不同呢
if we keep it going for the fans?
他們又不會知道
They'll never know.
我知道
I'll know.
你讓我顏面盡失  艾德
You made a chump out of me, Ed.
哈里  我們可以熬過去的
Harry, we can get through this.
我們可以揭穿瘦人的真相
We just debunk Thinman
然后繼續抓鬼特工隊的日子
and then we go back to Ghostfacers.
我做不到
I can't.
我再也不能相信你了  艾德
I can't trust you anymore, Ed.
別這樣  哈里
Oh, come on, Harry.
我明白  你生氣了
I get it. You're pissed, okay?
你所說的話都不是出自真心
And -- and you don't mean what you say.
哈里  告訴我你需要什么
But, Harry, just tell me what you need.
我去買咖啡
I'll go get some coffee, and --
你可以坐在這兒冷靜一下
and you can stay here and chill.
怎么樣
How did it go?
有點...
It, um, went, uh...um...
你沒事吧
You okay?
感覺被人胖揍了一頓
I just got punched right in the feels.
這一切都不是真的  薩姆
None of it was real, Sam.
艾德就是在裝模作樣  現在他還想要我假裝
Ed was just pretending, and now he wants me to pretend,
好像這一切沒什么大不了
like this is just something I could get past.
我懂你的意思
I know what you mean.
有些事你可以原諒
Look, there are things you can forgive,
有些事不行
and there are things you can't.
這件事算哪一種
So, which one is this?
你得自己考慮
That's something you got to figure out for yourself.
胎痕找到匹配的了  如果你想...
I got a bead on those tire treads, if you want to...
怎么了
What's up?
這種輪胎只有一種車用
So, the tires were only made for one kind of car.
1989年的吉優都市
It's a 1989 Geo Metro.
這么小的鎮子  這車只有一輛
Town this small -- there's only one registered here.
警官說是屬于一個叫羅杰的家伙
Deputy says it belongs to a guy named Roger
他在鎮子
who works night security
北面的工廠做夜班保安
down at the mill on the north side of town.
這東西既可以瞬移  又有工作有車
So, this thing teleported, but it has a job and car.
到底什么情況
What are we dealing with?
我們去看看
Let's go find out.
薩姆和迪恩有線索了
Sam and Dean caught something,
他們要去給你處理爛攤子了
so they're gonna clean up your mess.
你說得對  是我的爛攤子
You're right. It is my mess.
應該由我去處理
I should be the one out there cleaning it up.
你只會越幫越忙
You'd just make it worse.
怎么
Oh, what?
你又不是沒拋下他們不管過
You were fine leaving Sam and Dean before.
現在何必自找麻煩
Why not now?
我不想再做水母的脊柱了  哈里
I don't want to be a jellyfish spine anymore, Harry.
水母哪有脊柱
Jellyfish don't have spines.
正是
Exactly.
在心碎和謊言以前
Before the heartache, before the lies,
我們的出發點是幫助人  對嗎
we set out to help people, right?
對
Yeah.
主要是這樣
Mostly.
那我們沒道理不過去
So, there's no reason not to get out there
完成我們主要的出發點
and do what we mostly set out to do.
哈里  我可以彌補這件事
Harry, I-I can make this right for the both of us.
我們可以彌補這件事
We can make it right.
你的意思是要跟我一起去嗎
Y-you mean you want to come with me?
我們不是說了  我和我的搭檔會處理這事
I thought we said my partner and I would take care of this.
我上司不在
Look, guys, my boss is AWOL.
我們又沒有搜查令
We don't have a warrant.
這事出了岔子  我可就麻煩大了
My ass is on the line if this thing goes sideways.
好吧  你在后面跟著就好
All right. Just stay back.
一直想用用這些東西
Always wanted to use these things.
那么  你就是瘦人嗎
So, you're thinman, huh?
如果你不是那么胖
That would make sense
也倒能說得通了
if it didn't look Like you just ate a fat camp.
天吶  薩姆  讓他住口
Oh, god, Sam, make him stop.
這到底是怎么回事
Hey, so, what's the deal?
你到底是什么  諾伍德
What are you, Norwood?
是惡魔嗎
You a demon?
你是怎么瞬移進入餐館的
I mean, how did you teleport back at the diner?
團隊合作
Team effort.
根本沒什么瞬間移動
So, there was no teleporting --
只有幾個白癡在造謠生事
Just a couple of douche bags doing the "Scream" thing.
等等  我認得你
Wait, I know who you are.
你是那家餐廳的服務員
You're the busboy from the diner.
怎么  你就是想殺了你老板嗎
So, what, you just wanted to kill your boss?
特里是個人渣
Trey was a dick.
那凱茜呢
And what about Casey?
她怎么惹你了
What did she do?
她不愿意和我約會
She wouldn't go out with me,
所以我用別的東西招呼她
so I set her up with someone else,
我的刀子
my knife.
說得好  羅杰
Good one, Rog.
看來警長沒活著離開鎮子啊
I see the sheriff didn't make it out of town.
他應該給我我要求的假期的
Well, he really should have given me the time off I asked for.
你就為這個殺了他
So, you killed him?!
我誰也沒殺
I didn't kill anyone.
是羅杰殺的
Roger did.
他是個瘋子
He's the psycho.
而我是個夢想家
I'm the visionary.
我不怪你們輕視我
I don't blame you for underestimating me.
每個人都輕視我
Everybody does.
帥氣的探員  來到這兒
Fancy Fed, coming in here,
一開始就把我當成個小文員
treating me like a paper monkey from the get-go.
但其實我就是"瘦人"
But I was thinman the whole time.
你知道那種感覺有多棒嗎
Do you have any idea how good that felt?
不知道  變態  我還真不知道
No, sicko, I can't say that I do.
是啊  帥哥是不會知道
Yeah, pretty boy doesn't know
被人無視是什么感覺
what it's like to feel invisible --
在一個只有三百人的小鎮長大
To grow up in a town of 300 people
但是從沒有人注意過你
and nobody sees you.
他們看不見我們
They didn't see us.
那么  你倆是怎么認識的
So, how did you two meet?
通過"瘋子網"嗎
Wackjob.Com?
不是
No.
就是兩個呆子在一間空蕩蕩的酒吧相遇
Just a couple of schmoes in an empty bar.
我們一見如故
We hit it off.
我和羅杰
Turns out me and Rog --
居然都是陰謀論迷
we're both total conspiracy-theory junkies.
然后我們發現了"瘦人"
And then we found thinman, and, bam,
于是就轟炸了整個留言板
we blew up all over the message boards.
那這算什么  變態角色扮演嗎
So, what is this, then? Some sort of a twisted cosplay?
這是真人扮演
Cosreal.
發博客是很有趣  但是
You know, blogging was fun, but...
但是  讓我猜猜  你們想要更多
but, let me guess, you wanted something more.
你們知道你們倆混蛋做的事
You realize what you two jackasses are doing
并沒讓你成為"瘦人"
doesn't make you thinman.
你們只能算是模仿犯
It makes you copycat killers.
我就是"瘦人"
It makes me thinman.
而你沒辦法告訴別人我不是
And you're not telling anyone I'm not,
因為你馬上就要死透了
'cause you'll be too dead to talk.
好戲開場
Show time.
你倆真是幸運
You two are lucky ducks.
你們是我們目前為止最好的視頻的主演
You're the stars of our best video yet.
等視頻瘋傳
And when it goes viral,
大家都會知道"瘦人"是真的
everyone will know thinman's real.
準備  開拍
And...action!
等下  別別別  不要
Wait, no, no, no. Don't!
哈里
Harry...
他踢到了我  這是報復
Oh, he got me! He got me back!
現在是史酷比時刻  混蛋
It's scooby-doo time, douche bag.
史酷比·杜  美國動畫片角色
脫下面具
Take off the mask.
我知道你不是瘦人
I know you're not thinman.
你只是個"咪咪"
You're just a "me-me""
艾德  應該是彌母
Ed, it's pronounced meme.
文化傳播中起基因作用的媒介  泛指模仿者
可拼寫是M-E-M-E
It's spelled M-E-M-E, though.
第二個E不發音
The second "E" is silent. Yeah.
你只是個咪咪  是個人類彌母
You're a me-me -- a-a man-meme,
是我創造了你
and I invented you.
多謝賜教
Good to know.
我熱愛經典  艾德
I'm a lover of the classics, Ed.
我們正處于《弗蘭肯斯坦》式的情節中
And what we have here is a "Frankenstein" situation.
你居然是我的創造者
I mean, wow, the creator.
我們本打算放你們中的一人一條生路
I mean, we... we were gonna let one of you guys live
來傳頌我們的故事
to tell our story.
可現在
But now,
只要你們都死了  就沒人能證明
once you two are dead, there'll be no proof
瘦人是你們的創造
that thinman was your brainchild.
不
No.
別開槍  不  不要
Wait, no! No! No!
不  沖我來吧
No, look. Look at me.
都是我的錯
This is all my fault.
行嗎  都是我的錯
Okay? It's all my fault.
我槍里的子彈足夠弄死你們倆了
I got enough bullets for both of you.
-現場搞定了嗎  -是啊
- So, are we good in there? - Yeah.
瘦人的錄像加上我擺放尸體的方式
With the thinman footage and the way I set the bodies,
應該有足夠的線索讓別人以為
there should be enough breadcrumbs to make it look
是兩個瘋子同歸于盡
like those two psychos offed each other.
他們只是凡人  伙計
They were just people, man.
他們不是惡魔  也不是怪物
They weren't... demons. They weren't monsters.
他們  只是該死的凡人
They... were just frickin' people.
是啊  就像我說過的  人很變態
Yeah, well, like I said, people are sick.
那么  我們沒事了吧
S-so... are we cool?
我想我們不會和好如初了
I don't think we ever will be.
我們做出了彌補
I mean, you know, we made it right.
我們打敗了那些家伙
We, uh -- we beat the guys.
這可是我們抓鬼特工隊東山再起的好機會
This could be our shot to start the old ghostfacers again.
我跟你來這是為了解決瘦人的問題
I came here with you to finish this thing with thinman.
我不是想結束一個篇章  艾德
I wasn't just closing a chapter, Ed.
我是要結束這整本書
It was the whole dang book.
可你剛救了我的命
But you saved my life back there.
我殺了人  艾德
I killed a guy, Ed.
他是個壞蛋  哈里
He was a bad guy, Harry.
他也是個人  艾德
He was a guy, Ed.
太多人因為你的謊言喪命
Too many people have died 'cause of your crap.
我的謊言還不是為了我們
I've done all this crap for us.
我不知道為什么你看不出來
I-I don't know why you don't see that.
不  不
No. No.
你是為了自己
You did this for you.
艾德  我可以原諒很多事
Ed, there's a lot of things I can forgive,
但這事我無法原諒
but this isn't one of them.
那我們怎么辦
So, what does this mean about us?
我們...
It means...
一言難盡
it's complicated.
能載我一程嗎
Can I get a ride from you guys?
當然
Yeah, sure.
哈里  你還好吧
Harry, you okay?
是啊
Yeah.
我是說  不好
I mean, no.
你和一個人一起混那么多年
You roll with a guy so many years,
你甚至相信他會永遠和你在一起
you start to think he's always gonna be next to you.
就好像  等你老了  在門廊喝酒
like, when you're old and you're drinking on the porch,
他會坐在另一把搖椅上
he'll be in that other rocking chair.
可之后發生了些事
And then something happens,
你意識到
and you realize
另一把椅子上的人不見了
that other chair has gone empty.
懂我的意思嗎
You know what I mean?